Beer Pratap Singh

UI Developer

Beer Pratap Singh

Flat No. 103, B-Wing, Chakradhar Nagar, Nalasopara West (401203)

9892290204 biru.harshi@gmail.com

SKILLS -

HTML,CSS3, Jquery, Javascript, Angular Js, Angular JS Material, Bootstrap, MJML, Grunt, GIT, Photoshop As a highly-motivated and results driven UI Developer with 4+ years of experience in designing, developing, and managing complex e-commerce sites and internal frameworks.

Experience

Turtlemint / UI Developer

July 2017 - PRESENT,

Technologies used - HTML5, CSS3, LESS, SASS, Javascript, Angular Js, Bootstrap, Angular Material, MJML, Git, Jenkins, Visual Studio Code.

Designed & developed -

- Verticals landing pages like Car, Bike, Health and Life, as well as profile pages for B2C flow..
- Admin portal for B2B flow like MIS, Renewals, Payouts.
- Created HTML email templates.
- Maintaining blog of turtlemint.

Pepperfry / Sr. UI Developer

March 2016 - July 2017

Technologies used - HTML5, CSS3, LESS Javascript, Jquery, Zepto.js, Flexboxgrid css, Grunt, Git, Sublime Text.

Designed & developed -

- Revamped User Interface for web and mobile application for customer-facing e-commerce site with 100,000+ user visits per month.
- Optimized web and mobile application with the help of Grunt.js to improve site performance upto 30%.
- Created HTML email templates.

built.io / Web Engineer

June 2014 - March 2016

Technologies used - HTML5, CSS3, LESS, Jquery, Javascript, Foundation.Zurb, Grunt, Git, SVN, Sublime Text.

Designed & developed -

I worked there for a client **tibco.com**.

- Designed and developed front-end for 10+ websites, using HTML, CSS, jQuery, Javascript and AJAX.
- Created custom jquery and css components for internal framework.
- Developed parallax scrolling websites.

Education

Prasad Institute of Technology (U.P. Technical University Lucknow)

B.Tech with 66.14% aggregate 2013

J.I.C. birbhanpur Jaunpur (U.P.)

10th with 57.6% 2006

J.I.C. Birbhanpur Jaunpur (U.P.)

12th with 63.4% 2008

Interest

Reading, Traveling, Watching cricket & Gym.